<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Super Programmer</title>
    <description>Become that mythical super programmer every organization wishes they had.
</description>
    <link>http://superprogrammer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://superprogrammer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:21:25 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 10:21:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Super Programmer!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to up your programming chops to be the most effective coding machine you see romanticized in movies and called out in every job posting looking for software engineers. It’s time to become Super Programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego Check Time&lt;/strong&gt;
This isn’t about becoming some mythical programmer who can hack into the matrix, read binary, and flip bits using &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/378/&quot;&gt;butterfly wings.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also isn’t me declaring that I think I have super human programmer powers or that I’m any better, smarter, or more talented than the average software developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is an aspiration. An endless pursuit of being better by giving (and hopefully receiving) practical advice on how to do what appears from the outside as super human with less effort. Because as we all know, the best programmers are the lazy programmers; The ones that will when tasked with doing something that takes 5 minutes, instead take a few hours to learn bash scripting, find themselves in the weeds about the best way to handle a variable from the command line, wonder if this could be done better in python, realize you’ve gone way too far down this path and finally come back around to what you were trying to solve in the first place and automate that original task so you never have to manually do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we’ll learn what’s worth spending time on, where you’ll get the most gains as perceived from your team, your organization and your own workload so you can feel proud, accomplished, and not overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://superprogrammer.com/blog/sticky/2019/01/01/welcome-to-super-programmer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://superprogrammer.com/blog/sticky/2019/01/01/welcome-to-super-programmer.html</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        <category>introduction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>sticky</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
